Guide to the Center for Information on America Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Center for Information on America records
1951-1985
MS 1855
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16
The records consist of correspondence with fund granting agencies and academicians who wrote for the Center for Information on America's publications, subject files, financial records, copies of the Center's publications and related circulation files, and administrative records.
Center for Information on America
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Thayer Scudder, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged by type of material.
Biographical / Historical
The Center for Information on America was founded in 1951 in Washington, Connecticut. Townsend Scudder 3rd (1900-1988) served as executive director during its existence. Its purpose was devoted to the broad aim of furthering public understanding of this country's self-governing process and the issues faced in continuing the successful operation of democracy. The goals of the Center were realized through a series of publications, including Vital Issues, Grass Roots Guides on Democracy and Practical Politics, and Capital. The Center closed in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence with fund granting agencies and academicians who wrote for the Center for Information on America's publications, subject files, financial records, copies of the Center's publications and related circulation files, and administrative records.
Scudder, Townsend, 1900-; Center for Information on America
- Inventory
  - Meetings/minutes, 1952-1985 (Box 1)
  - Meetings/minutes, 1952-1985 (Box 2)
  - Meetings/minutes, 1952-1985 (Box 3)
  - Meetings/minutes, 1952-1985 (Box 4)
  - Meetings/minutes, 1952-1985 (Box 5)
  - Circulation reports, 1958-1970, 1979, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Financial [includes audits], 1951-1983 (Box 7)
  - Publications, 1950s-1970s (Box 8)
  - Publications, 1950s-1970s (Box 9)
  - Administrative [includes background on the Center], 1951-1985 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence/subject files, 1950s-1980s
    - A-B (Box 11)
    - B-C (Box 12)
    - D-F (Box 13)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 14)
    - F-P (Box 15)
    - R-Z (Box 16)